Ben Amies-King

CONTACT Information

bamiesking@gmail.com

 $+44\ 7720\ 642878$

linkedin.com/in/bamiesking/

STATEMENT

I'm a motivated, high-performing student with an excellent combination of technical and interpersonal skills, and with experience of planning and working to a tight schedule. I pride myself on having an open-minded outlook and taking a rational and inclusive approach to discussion, and being a respectful but assertive team member.

EDUCATION

University of Durham

MPhys Physics (Integrated Masters), graduating in 2021

1st at Level 2 (2018-19); scores of 95% in Mathematical Methods in Physics and 83% in Theoretical Physics 2.

2:1 at Level 1 (2017-18); average of 71% across Physics modules.

Tadcaster Grammar School

A levels

A* in Maths, Further Maths.

A in Physics, German, and AS Chemistry.

GCSEs

A* in Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, English Literature.

A in English Language, Additional Maths, Religious Education, Economics, ICT, German.

B in Music.

EMPLOYMENT

MyTutor

Online Tutor

Sep. 2017 to present

My profile: goo.gl/bCTeqP

- Planning and delivering high-quality tutorials at GCSE and A level for a large number of clients, with over 400 completed sessions and 200 five-star reviews.
- Maintaining effective and professional communication with parents and students, and developing a good rapport.
- Providing friendly but firm advice with underperforming students.
- Following strict safeguarding procedures to ensure child safety.
- Managing finances and running a business.

Tadcaster Grammar School

Senior Supervisory Assistant

Jul. 2016 to Apr. 2017

- Responsible for supervising a large area of school grounds.
- Dealing with students' issues and de-escalating conflict.
- Building good relationships with challenging students to avoid confrontation.
- Issuing sanctions including detention according to a standardised system.

EXPERIENCE

Student Leadership

Vice-Treasurer, St Aidan's College JCR

Oct. 2019 to present

- Responsible for working within Finance Committee to coordinate organisational and financial growth and development of JCR.
- Developing a handover process for JCR roles from the ground up, to ensure smooth running of crucial committees during annual reelections.

House Captain, Tadcaster Grammar School

Nov. 2015 to Oct. 2016

- Led a team of 10 students through various projects, delegating and assigning roles and responsibilities.
- Organised and chaired regular meetings.
- Implemented a successful mentoring scheme with zero financial cost.

Work Experience

United Utilities 2014

- Processed site information in a successful multi-million pound bid.
- Carried out testing on a new custom software package.
- Assisted in various administrative capacities.

Volunteering

Durham University SCA Tutoring

Copmanthorpe Methodist Church Holiday Club

Institute of Physics Outreach: York Festival of Ideas

AMP Awards: Event Organisation and Fundraising

Nov. 2018 to present

Jul. 2018

Jun. 2018

2014 to 2016

Other

NCS Jul. 2016

SKILLS

Personal

- Excellent communication skills.
- Intermediate German (spoken and written).
- Strong desire to learn and improve.

Technical

- Proficient in LATEX and Python.
- Familiar with Microsoft Office.
- Experience with web development and design.